

Niranjan Iyer, Retail Banker

BANGALORE, INDIA · iyer.niranjan@gmail.com

DETAILS

Bangalore, India +917338285265

LINKS

LinkedIn

SKILLS

Retail Banking

MS Office

LANGUAGES

English

Tamil

Hindi

Malayalam

Kannada

PROFILE

To work with a reputed, growth-oriented organization with professional outlook and to excel in any field of activity and emerge as a unique and successful employee. Have gained varied experiences for the past 16 years in challenging environments. Possess excellent analytical and problem-solving skills, ability to deal with multilingual people with good leadership qualities and computer skills.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Teller Authoriser-Manager, HDFC Bank

May 2018 — Mar 2020, Tumkur

- Authorisation of all Cheques and Cash Vouchers worth above INR 50,000.
- Authorisation of all clearing cheques on a daily basis and send all cheques to Wholesale Banking Operation Team.
- Authorisation of salary upload and to ensure that proper follow up is done with Back End Team.
- Checking of cash at EOD and ensure cash is safely kept in the Vault on a daily basis.
- Ensure that the cash is sent to Currency Chest and to other branches at regular intervals.
- Ensure all the EOD activities related to the teller counter are done as per the process of the management.
- Manage the tellers in the teller counter and ensure that they are delivering best services to the customers
- To resolve all queries of customers related to the teller counter.
- Ensure that the customers are provided best services within the prescribed time frame.

Senior Executive, Xpress Money Services - Global Head Quarters

Apr 2010 — Aug 2017, Dubai

- Primarily responsible for servicing all Regional Offices spread across USA, UK, Europe, Middle East, Australia etc.
- Co-ordinate with the staff and/or agents in various countries and to assist in the creation and
 maintenance of their respective agent codes and login credentials.
- Agent code, login credentials etc. based on the agent matrix for the old as well as new branches
 and additional locations of Xpress Money Agents.
- Monitor and help the agents all over the globe with system related queries.
- Work along with the support team in resolving settlement issues with the agents.
- Co-ordinate with the Digital Certificate team in certifying the computers for all the configured agents.
- Implement new work procedures for the Xpress Money system.
- To issue timely circulars for all the developments within the Organization.

Supervisor, Golden Goal Services

Aug 2008 — Jan 2010, Abu Dhabi

- Maintain the security cash deposit on daily basis.
- Pay all the winning customers.

- Maintenance of tickets on daily basis.
- Support to sales staff in improving ticket sales.
- Handling customer queries.
- Facilitating inspection at regular intervals.

Clerical Administrator, RAKBANK

Mar 2007 — May 2008, Dubai

PDC Dept.:

- · Daily Clearing Activity.
- Co-ordinate between various Departments in collecting details for various activities related to PDC.
- Obsolete the Deals as instructed by concerned departments..
- Dispatch the cheque packets of settled deals to the customers and branches.
- Handling queries related to PDC Department.

Out-Sourcing and Fax Control Dept.:

- Distribution of faxes and reports to the concerned departments.
- · Maintenance of records and files and issue them on request.
- Liaising with the outsourcing companies.
- Co-ordination and tracking of file transfer between departments and head office
- Handling queries related to file distribution.
- Sending acknowledgements to all branches at EOD.

Channel Manager, ICICI Lombard General Insurance

Jan 2005 — Feb 2007, Bhopal

- Recruit and develop agents at the sales front.
- · Develop channel management.
- Achieve monthly and yearly targets.
- Assisting agents and sales officers reporting to me with regard to sales promotion.
- · Attend regular meetings at regional office.
- Have a good rapport with all customers and provide excellent services.
- No. of reportees Two sales officers along with 30 agents.

Clerical Staff, UTI Bank Ltd

Jul 2004 — Dec 2004, Nagpur

- · Responsible for opening various types of new bank accounts.
- Handling the walk-in customers into the branch in guiding them to the respective desk and solving their queries.
- Sourcing business from the walk-in customers on various products from time to time.
- Supported the branch staff with the day to day activities and earned good recognition on the same
- Assisting other departments in addition to my responsibilities.

Intern, ICICI Bank Limited

Dec 2003 — Jun 2004, Nagpur

- Opening various types of new bank accounts with regards to Cash Management Services and Corporate account opening.
- Good co-ordination with customer and other staff, attending to customer's complaints.
- Met and interacted with top management of various organizations in and around Nagpur City.
- Assisting other departments in addition to my responsibilities.

EDUCATION

Madurai Kamaraj University, Masters Degree in Financial Control

Jun 2001 — Apr 2003, Madurai

Madurai Kamaraj University, Bachelor of Commerce

Jun 1996 — May 1999, Madurai

ACHIEVEMENTS

I CAUGHT YOU

DUBAI

Received an "I CAUGHT YOU" award for having successfully completed the Project on encoding cheques together with day-to-day activities.

Global Employee of the Month

Dubai

Continuously achieved the maximum target from June to October 2015 at UAE level and subsequently was Awarded "Global Employee of the Month" in August 2015.

REFERENCES

References available upon request